the risk of global stagflation is making
investors nervous
msci emerging market index and msci
world index have declined 20 percent in
the year 2022.
hi i am saurav kumar and i am joined
here by sameer bharathwaj he writes for
et wealth and in this video we are going
to discuss stocks that have shown strong
resistance to market downturns and
correction thanks amir for joining us so
uh samir what's uh increasing the stock
market volatility okay so so as you've
already mentioned about the global risks
of global stagnation so stagflation is
basically the economic phenomena where
the higher inflation is accompanied by
the low low economic growth okay so this
is one of the point that is making
investors nervous the other thing is
that the the first quarter uh
things are coming up and if you look at
the preview reports from quarter
securities and philip capital so there
is a quarter there will be a quarter and
quarter decline in the the net profit
groups okay so the reasons basically for
these the decline is the ongoing
supplied disruptions basically high
power fuel cost and decline the volume
due to lower exports
okay so these are the reasons why the
volatility has been rising about the
corrections uh that have come uh so how
many corrections have come in the in the
last uh few years if you see we have
identified five corrections basically so
if you look at the first correction most
of these corrections are triggered by
external factors okay so if you look at
the first correction if you look at the
first correction it is traded by the
chinese uh markets uh sell down in the
year in january 2015 and it continued
till february 2016. okay then six lost
around 22.7 during this period
okay the second correction was taken by
us china trade wars uh it was between
august 2018 and october 2018 and the
markets have actually tanked 14.3
percent
the third correction basically was uh
during uh 2009 between june 2019 and
september 2019 when the india government
has returned to one and also the markets
were reacting that time because the
the government was actually preparing or
presenting uh the first full uh budget
okay so that was the thing that that has
increased the volatility markets have
actually lost around ten point four
percent during that second time nda
government came to power yeah yes yes
okay yeah the fourth correction was
recently they are doing the onset of
overweight
markets have actually corrected over 38
between january 2020 and march 2020 and
uh the fifth correction is between is
the latest correction basically between
october 2 and 21 of the markets at the
peak basically and uh between the seven
between june 20
stocks that have kind of
resisted all these uh
market corrections so let let me first
uh tell you while where you were trying
to find out those talk what kind of uh
methodology
did you use in finding out that stock
okay see the thing is that uh because of
the risk that we are that i've already
mentioned uh we wanted to look at some
stocks that have uh that have uh
performed better during the during the
market corrections or during the market
okay so
we wanted to look at stocks that have
actually lost less than their benchmark
the benchmark here defined as bse
sensitive okay or those that have gained
during the during those uh market
creation period okay so those five
corrections that we have identified we
tried to look at the performance of
stocks and the performance of the
benchmark bc synthetics so uh we only
consider stocks that have market cap
greater than one thousand crores to uh
to eliminate small and to element
basically small customers you're saying
a market cap of one thousand crore so
what was the timeline of the that you
took uh for identifying the correction
we we used the data for the last 10
years we we look at the bsc closing
values bc closing prices from
june 2012 to 2022. so on that basis we
define them we look at the market peaks
and drops and uh a minimum fall of 10
percent from the peak to trough which we
identified as a correction now the other
thing that the other thing was that the
difference between the peak interrupts
it has to be a minimum of eight weeks or
two months okay so on that basis we
identified the five correction that we
have already discussed how did you find
out the fundamental soundness of those
stocks okay so once we have uh
determined the five corrections now we
looked at stocks that have that have
actually lost less than the benchmark or
have gained more than that okay we we
got a we got some shortlisted stocks now
to uh to make sure that these stocks are
fundamentally sound we looked at some
fundamental metrics we used uh 10 years
annual data from from fy to 13 to fi 22
and we looked at the three ratios
basically one is the dividend payout
ratio yeah the year year on year eps
growth and the return on equity all this
data is extracted from bloomberg okay so
we talked about uh year-on-year eps
growth if you could tell uh
this is basically the earning per share
how much the company is actually earning
on a per share basis so that way we
looked at last 10 years data for the ep
score okay companies whose last 10 year
average of all these three uh metrics is
greater than 15 percent
okay so uh the other thing is that
you only look at those companies that
have reported positive eps in all of the
last 10 years so that way we may make
sure that the company is fundamentally
support okay so on that basis uh we
identified some five stocks so i i think
if uh you have identified five stocks
and their prospects going forward so the
first one i think is the tcs why did you
choose this stock see tcs is actually uh
like uh just killed all the filters that
we have applied so it's actually uh
it has
shown good resistance during the market
correction and also
failed better on the fundamental metrics
that we have used so if you look at the
future prospects of this company this
company has uh reported an inline growth
during the first quarter 2023
in different verticals now those
verticals are consumer package goods
retail segments communication media and
bfsi okay okay so apart from that the
company is also generated with a good
free cash inflows and
that is a key positive for the company
in the current quarter in the near to
medium term the demand environment is
likely to remain strong so as a result
the company's deal bookings
will be robust so these are the
um
and also like the company is likely to
improve its operating margin in the next
three quarters so let's get to the
second one what's the second stock that
you think has a very good growth
prospect the second one is the power
grid corporation power grid corporation
is a steady performer due to its recent
asset editions in the past few years
also like the the company is exploring
uh smart metered meter business very
expecting a good irr that's the internal
data okay okay the other thing is that
it is also emerging as a key player in
the battery energy storage system okay
uh
also it has the presence across value
chain and aims to improve government
transmission and distribution system so
uh
it is also falling into the solar power
generation so in terms of renewables
also the companies like it's doing
better and uh capex of the company is
very high and uh according to jp morgan
report uh it says that the capex will be
the near-term growth driver for the
company okay so these are some of the
reasons why we look at the
corporations okay
now let's talk about the i think it's a
chemical company srf so uh how do you
see its growth prospects so srf is a
specialty chemicals company and uh as
you like the specialty chemicals are
like the segment is poised to grow
basically because of the uh government
policies like tax incentives pli schemes
and
uh export opportunities are there then
there are the productive machines are
there so these are some of the factors
that are expected to benefit specialty
chemical segment now coming to the
company itself like it has a
uh it's fluorochemical business segment
basically it's likely to benefit uh
because of the strong refrigerant gas
environment gasoline
okay so the packaging segment will be
supported by the
the strong demand for packaging films so
i think the fourth stock is also an uh
specialized chemical company what's that
yeah the fourth stock is it's naveen
flooring interaction it's also a
specialty chemical company now the
company uh is likely to benefit from a
healthy order book that provides strong
growth visibility going forward okay the
other thing is that the there is a
robust growth prospects in the crime
segment and also like the there is the
company's strong pricing power in the in
organic farewed segment i think uh after
i t power and two chem specialized
chemical companies the fifth one is a
beverage company yeah the fifth one is
ccl products so the company like it will
be a beneficiary of high coffee prices
okay and uh
it's expanding its capacity in vietnam
so that will also be beneficial for the
company going forward also the company
has a aggressive distribution plans in
the domestic uh domestic segment and uh
the economies of scale and strong
customer relationship with other
stockholders
okay so there you go these are the five
stocks which are most likely to weather
the upcoming storm according to the
research done by e.t wealth
[Music]